## **Dr Victor Maus**

Senior Researcher

**Curriculum Vitae** September 2021 **♀** Welthandelsplatz 1, 1020 Vienna, Austria

victor-maus.com

+43 1 31336 6176

vwmaus1@gmail.com

@victor\_maus

vwmaus

in victor-maus-083a79191

**G** wN2LseQAAAAJ&hl

**d** 0000-0002-7385-4723

I am a researcher in Geoinformatics and Spatial Data Science with application in sustainability science, in particular landuse changes. I am the author of Time-Weighted Dynamic Time Warping (TWDTW) algorithm, to classify Earth observation time series in data-scarce conditions. I have implemented the TWDTW as open-source in my R package dtwSat. I have also led the production of the first-ever spatially-explicit global assessment of mining land use to assess the environmental impacts and sustainability of the global mining sector.

## **EDUCATION**

2016	<b>PhD in Earth System Science</b> São José dos Campos, Brazil	National Institute for Space Research (INPE)
2011	<b>MSc in Computational Modeling</b> Juiz de Fora, Brazil	Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)
2009	<b>BSc in Environmental Engineering</b> Santa Maria, Brazil	Franciscan University (UFN)

## **CURRENT POSITIONS**

2018-	Senior Researcher	Vienna University of Economics and Business (WU)
	Vienna, Austria	
2016-	Research Scholar	International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA)
	Laxenburg Austria	

## **PREVIOUS POSITIONS**

2014-2016	Research Assistant Münster, Germany	University of Münster (WWU)
2012-2014	<b>University Lecturer</b> Itaqui, Brazil	Federal University of Pampa (UNIPAMPA)
2011-2012	<b>Research Assistant</b> São José dos Campos, Brazil	National Institute for Space Research (INPE)
2009-2011	<b>Research Assistant</b> Juiz de Fora, Brazil	Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)

FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS
SUPERVISION OF STUDENTS
TEACHING ACTIVITIES
INSTITUTIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES
REVIEWING ACTIVITIES
PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Luckeneder, S., Giljum, S., Schaffartzik, A., Maus, V., & Tost, M. (2021). Surge in global metal mining threatens vulnerable ecosystems. *Global Environmental Change*, 69, 102303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2021. 102303
- 2. Maus, V., Giljum, S., Gutschlhofer, J., Silva, D. M. da, Gass, S. L. B., Luckeneder, S., Lieber, M., & McCallum, I. (2020). A global-scale data set of mining areas. *Scientific Data*, 7(1), 289. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-020-00624-w

- 3. Bruckner, M., Wood, R., Moran, D., Kuschnig, N., Wieland, H., **Maus, V.**, & Börner, J. (2019). FABIO-the construction of the food and agriculture biomass input-output model. *Environmental Science & Technology*, *53*(19), 11302–11312. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b03554
- 4. Stanimirova, R., Arévalo, P., Kaufmann, R. K., **Maus, V.**, Lesiv, M., Havlík, P., & Friedl, M. A. (2019). Sensitivity of global pasturelands to climate variation. *Earth's Future*. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019EF001316
- 5. Maus, V., Câmara, G., Appel, M., & Pebesma, E. (2019). dtwSat: Time-Weighted Dynamic Time Warping for Satellite Image Time Series Analysis in R. *Journal of Statistical Software*, 88(5), 1–31. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v088.i05
- 6. Bruckner, M., Häyhä, T., Giljum, S., **Maus, V**., Fischer, G., Tramberend, S., & Börner, J. (2019). Quantifying the global cropland footprint of the european union's non-food bioeconomy. *Environmental Research Letters*, 14(4), 045011. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab07f5
- 7. Hadi, Krasovskii, A., **Maus, V.**, Yowargana, P., Pietsch, S., & Rautiainen, M. (2018). Monitoring Deforestation in Rainforests Using Satellite Data: A Pilot Study from Kalimantan, Indonesia. *Forests*, *9*(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/f9070389
- 8. See, L., Laso Bayas, J. C., Schepaschenko, D., Perger, C., Dresel, C., Maus, V., Salk, C., Weichselbaum, J., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Moorthy, I., & Fritz, S. (2017). LACO-Wiki: A New Online Land Cover Validation Tool Demonstrated Using GlobeLand30 for Kenya. *Remote Sensing*, 9(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs9070754
- 9. Furlan, V. J. M., **Maus, V**., Batista, I., & Bandarra, N. M. (2017). Production of docosahexaenoic acid by Auranti-ochytrium sp. ATCC PRA-276. *Brazilian Journal of Microbiology*, 48(2), 359–365. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjm. 2017.01.001
- 10. **Maus, V.**, Camara, G., Cartaxo, R., Sanchez, A., Ramos, F. M., & Queiroz, G. R. de. (2016). A time-weighted dynamic time warping method for land-use and land-cover mapping. *IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing*, *9*(8), 3729–3739. https://doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2016.2517118
- 11. Furlan, V. J. M., Castelo Paulo, M. do, **Maus, V**., Ferreira, J., Batista, I., & Bandarrac, N. M. (2016). Production of docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) from Thraustochytrium sp. ATCC 26185 using different nitrogen concentrations. *Boletim Centro de Pesquisa de Processamento de Alimentos*, 34(2), 1–11. https://doi.org/10.5380/cep.v34i2. 53189
- See, L., Schepaschenko, D., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Fritz, S., Comber, A., Perger, C., Schill, C., Zhao, Y., Maus, V., Siraj, M. A., Albrecht, F., Cipriani, A., Vakolyuk, M., Garcia, A., Rabia, A. H., Singha, K., Marcarini, A. A., Kattenborn, T., ... Obersteiner, M. (2015). Building a hybrid land cover map with crowdsourcing and geographically weighted regression. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 103, 48–56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2014.06.016
- 13. **Maus, V.**, Costa, A. B. da, & Righes, A. A. (2009). Tratamento do lixiviado de aterro de resíduos sólidos urbanos por processo fenton. *Tecno-Lógica*, 13(1), 52–59. https://doi.org/10.17058/tecnolog.v13i1.931